<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Dirk's Home Page - Fun</title><link href="//colbrydi.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//colbrydi.github.io/feeds/fun.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//colbrydi.github.io/</id><updated>2018-05-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>FarmBot</title><link href="//colbrydi.github.io/farmbot.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Dirk Colbry</name></author><id>tag:colbrydi.github.io,2018-05-27:/farmbot.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been coveting a &lt;a href="//farm.bot/"&gt;FarmBot&lt;/a&gt;.  At $2500 to $4000 these farming robots are a little out of my price range. However, I guess if I had a big enough yard I would still be looking to purchase one of these. They are so cool, they will plant, water, weed …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been coveting a &lt;a href="//farm.bot/"&gt;FarmBot&lt;/a&gt;.  At $2500 to $4000 these farming robots are a little out of my price range. However, I guess if I had a big enough yard I would still be looking to purchase one of these. They are so cool, they will plant, water, weed your garden for you.  So much fun!  And you get to eat the product when you are done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company uses open source hardware so I guess I could try to build it on my own and save a little money. All of the tools are built using 3D Printing so there is that.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project would go well with my robotic composting project I want to build.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Maker"></category><category term="Product Reviews"></category><category term="3DPrinting"></category></entry><entry><title>JJRobotics</title><link href="//colbrydi.github.io/jjrobotics.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Dirk Colbry</name></author><id>tag:colbrydi.github.io,2018-05-19:/jjrobotics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A great purchase for anyone with a 3D printer and looking for projects With the kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a year ago I stubbled across &lt;a href="//www.jjrobots.com/"&gt;JJRobots&lt;/a&gt; and I just love the idea of this company.  They sell a kit of electronic parts to maker hobbyists with access to 3D printers.   The idea …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A great purchase for anyone with a 3D printer and looking for projects With the kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a year ago I stubbled across &lt;a href="//www.jjrobots.com/"&gt;JJRobots&lt;/a&gt; and I just love the idea of this company.  They sell a kit of electronic parts to maker hobbyists with access to 3D printers.   The idea is that you use your 3D printer to make the items and everything you can't print is in the kit provided by JJRobots.  They spend their time developing new products that you can print with the same kit.  For example, the kit I purchased can be used to build the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marker board writer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eggbot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robotic arm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motorized Camera slider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mini Robotic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Air Hocky Robot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I have only built the Eggbot but it was awesome!  We spent last easter painting egg shells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;Pictures here&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately that print was tricky and my printer has been on the fritz lately (see other posts) and I haven't had the time/space to fix it.  However, my family and I are moving to a bigger house with a dedicated maker space so I hope to start working on projects again.  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Maker"></category><category term="Product Reviews"></category></entry><entry><title>CNC Mill Picking</title><link href="//colbrydi.github.io/cnc-mill-picking.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Dirk Colbry</name></author><id>tag:colbrydi.github.io,2018-05-18:/cnc-mill-picking.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am interested in purchasing a CNC machine for the shop space in our new house.  I think I would like to stick to something around $1000 but would be willing to invest as much as $2000 if I can find the right machine.  There are a lot of choices …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am interested in purchasing a CNC machine for the shop space in our new house.  I think I would like to stick to something around $1000 but would be willing to invest as much as $2000 if I can find the right machine.  There are a lot of choices in this price range for hobby CNC machines.  Some other selection criteria include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big cut area (I would love 4'x8' but that seems a lot) - I am interested in trying out thigns you can do with furniture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small detailed work - I also have a few small projects that require detail.  I realize it will be difficult to have a machine that does both big and small.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open source hardware (I just like these projects) - Something I can easily modify with a rich user community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my inicial search I came accross the following systems and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="//sienci.com/product/sienci-mill-one-kit/"&gt;Sienci&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="//diylilcnc.org/bigshoulders/"&gt;DiyLilcnc&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="//carbide3d.com/shapeoko/"&gt;Shapeoko&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="//www.inventables.com/technologies/x-carve/"&gt;X-Carve&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="//openbuilds.com/?category=cartesian-style-cnc&amp;amp;id=287"&gt;Openbuild community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just stumbled across the &lt;a href="//www.maslowcnc.com/"&gt;Maslow&lt;/a&gt; and got really excited. The large format capabilities (4'x8') with the really low price ($350) would leave more than enough in my budget to buy two machines.  In fact, I may be able to buy a Maslow and then use it to make the parts I would need another project like the DiyLilcnc (Although I just realized the kickstart for that is relly old 2011).  There are probably other projects.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Maker"></category><category term="CNC"></category></entry></feed>