<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Dirk's Home Page - images</title><link href="//colbrydi.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//colbrydi.github.io/feeds/images.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//colbrydi.github.io/</id><updated>2014-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Light Box</title><link href="//colbrydi.github.io/light-box.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2014-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Dirk Colbry</name></author><id>tag:colbrydi.github.io,2014-05-11:/light-box.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In addition to making, I love to take pictures. Photography has been a passion
of mine since I was my daughter's age. I remember one vacation in Lake
Michigan with my family: my Aunt Pat gave me a 110 cartridge camera and
basically just let me loose. I was hooked …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In addition to making, I love to take pictures. Photography has been a passion
of mine since I was my daughter's age. I remember one vacation in Lake
Michigan with my family: my Aunt Pat gave me a 110 cartridge camera and
basically just let me loose. I was hooked. The only problem with my habit was
the cost of developing film, which I tried to pay for in high school by
working at a one hour developing store and in college by working on the
newspaper and yearbook. Finally, even though the resolution was poor, digital
cameras allowed me to feed my habit - and as they continuously get better I
haven't looked back.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the plans for this light box on the internet (&lt;a href="http://digital-photography-school.com/how-to-make-a-inexpensive-light-tent"&gt;http://digital-photography-school.com/how-to-make-a-inexpensive-light-tent&lt;/a&gt;) and thought it
would make a good project for me and my kids. A light box will also come in
handy if we need to take pictures of the things we are making.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step was to measure and cut the box. This is where we got stuck
because the cardboard paper I had was a little old and yellowish. I wanted
something cleaner so I had to set this project aside until I could by some
better cardboard (and cloth, while I was at it).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="./images/small_LIght1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/small_LIght1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up buying Bristol board as recommend in the blog post. It has a nice
smooth finish and I think it will work well.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="./images/small_Light2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/small_Light2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My daughter and I cut out strips of the board and glued them to the box.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="./images/small_Light3.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/small_Light3.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once glued, we added the cloth and tested it out on my android phone.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="./images/small_Light4.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/small_Light4.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This looks okay, although I think I need some better (and brighter) lights -
but this looks to be a good start.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="./images/small_Light5.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/small_Light5.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogpost migrated from &lt;a href="https://apprenticemaker.blogspot.com/2014/05/light-box.html"&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt; using costom python script. Comment on errors below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Maker"></category><category term="3DPrinting"></category></entry></feed>