<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Dirk's Blog - Personal</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/personal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>My First Blog Post</title><link href="/my-first-blog-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Dirk Colbry</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-06-22:/my-first-blog-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello World&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello World&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Lifehacking"></category></entry><entry><title>Spark mail</title><link href="/spark-mail.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Dirk Colbry</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-06-06:/spark-mail.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am weird that I like email.  It is my preferred form of communication on projects (maybe I am just getting old).  I trust that I will get to my email and that I will not loose things.  I realize that this trust is often not true but it is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am weird that I like email.  It is my preferred form of communication on projects (maybe I am just getting old).  I trust that I will get to my email and that I will not loose things.  I realize that this trust is often not true but it is true enough for me to keep productive. For the longest time Gmail was my favorite email application. However, work changed policy from "we highly recommend you don't use Gmail" to "don't use gmail".  So I chose to switch to the university Office 365 accounts.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried the built-in Mac mail program.  It didn't thread my email the way I prefer.  I also tried outlook which had its own problems.  I don't really feel like bashing this software, it just didn't work in a way that fit my Gmail workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I move into a new laptop I stubbled across the spark email client. About three weeks into using it I am very satisfied. The laptop and phone versions work nicely together. I really like having both my personal Gmail account and work accounts connected in one application.  There are a lot of things I like but probably the best is that since using Spark I have gotten my inbox to zero almost every day.  This is big news. I am a big fan of emptying my inbox but this is often a challenge.  I like the fact that Spark will allow me to show badges with the number of messages in my inbox instead of the number of unread messages.  For some reason this is a real motivator for getting my email where they need to be. It also helps me keep my Gmail clean which is mostly news feeds, advertisements, etc.  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Review"></category><category term="Lifehacking"></category></entry><entry><title>Back to Blogging</title><link href="/back-to-blogging.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Dr. Dirk Colbry</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-05-18:/back-to-blogging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of blogging but often have difficulty in the delivery.  A few years ago I maintained a blog when I worked for the Institute for Cyber-Enabled Research (iCER) at Michigan State University (MSU). At iCER I did a lot of High Performance Computing (HPC) User support. This …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of blogging but often have difficulty in the delivery.  A few years ago I maintained a blog when I worked for the Institute for Cyber-Enabled Research (iCER) at Michigan State University (MSU). At iCER I did a lot of High Performance Computing (HPC) User support. This involved mostly helping researchers figure out how to use advanced computing systems in their research.  I got into a habit of writing up a blog post when I learned something new or figured out a solution to a practical technical problem.  I also found the blog useful for posting slides and examples from presentations I would often make at workshops and conferences. Many of these old posts are still see a little traffic. Check them out here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://wiki.hpcc.msu.edu/display/~colbrydi@msu.edu/Dirk%27s+iCER+wiki+homepage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also did some blogging related to my kids and our "maker" hobby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://apprenticemaker.blogspot.com/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I moved away from working directly for iCER and have not done a good job keeping up with my maker blog. I am going to try to bring the blogging habit back into my workflow.   I am currently in the middle of quite a few projects relating to education and large scale computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a couple of goals for writing a blog. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting over my reluctance to share and communicate in online communities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping me organize and be accountable for my projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connecting with people with similar interests to my own&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing informations that others may find helpful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reach these goals I am going to try to get into a daily habit of writing.  I don't think I will post a blog everyday but the writing habit is important to me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Lifehacking"></category></entry></feed>